Adding items in queue is known as in queue.
So consider this queue, this empty Q and these elements one, two and three in order to add element
one inside the HQ inside the queue.
We call the method in queue and pass that data number one, so we pass the value of the element that
we are going to insert inside the queue.
So in Q1, it will insert element one inside the queue.
In Q2, it will add the queue number two and in Q3 it will add to the queue number three.
Let's see that code in C the fine size three.
We are going to create a queue, an array.
So remember you is an array also.
And size array it size the same size and into four aren't equal to zero, and in three are equal to
zero.
We have created two variables.
Front and rear, and they are at indexer, void in queue.
It took into meter that value of the data that we are going to insert inside a free or equal equal to
size, then the queue is full.
OK, if we have moved that ear into their size and we have checked that, that is equal to size, then
that's useful.
Otherwise, it will create a new element at a rate of index three here equal to Vall, and we increase
it here by one.
So how to do how this works?
Consider we have a queue, this queue is about, and it is formed of an array of size defined as three.
OK.
And now we are going to insert data inside it.
This is an empty array.
It's an empty queue.
Remember a queue and the stack based on a an array?
OK.
You can make a stack with link, at least.
And you can make a cue with it and list.
But till now, we we we need to make this using that array.
So this queue formed of three cells.
Size equal to three have eight in the zero array index.
One in the array at index two.
We have created two integers the front and rear.
They are pointing at index zero.
If I called them method in queue and passed 100, it will check if they're equal equal to size.
Rear is equal to zero.
And the size is equal to three.
So this will not be the first.
If condition is not execute, it will execute the else part.
So array at index three or make it equal to that.
So array at index zero make it equal to 100.
This is the.
The code and the real plus plus increase the rear by one.
OK.
This is their algorithm that is behind the NQ method inside the queue.
If I call the method in queue to 200.
Again, it will check a freer, equal equal to size.
No rear is equal to one and size is equal to three.
So we are not we are not going to execute the if part we are going to execute the as part as part tell
us to make their array at index three, which is one now is equal to van.
So put 200 inside this index and increase the rear plus a glass.
So move the rear to one plus one.
If I call the method in queue 300, I will check if they're equal to size.
No two is not equal to three.
Then put array at Index three or at index two is equal to 300.
Then move rear plus one.
Now, rear indicates an empty.
Position or equal to size?
If I call now in Q400, it will check if rear equal to size.
Yes.
So rear is three and the size is three.
Then if I call the Inc you after this, it will put into print for us.
Q. Is.